{
    "id": "a1d57e5d201b4626acf421ddd31caa90",
    "title": "Mixed Conditional Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "7f051e72994e4c92bda3709874279bdd",
            "title": "Mixed Conditionals Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "If I were you, I …………………………… this.",
                    "description": "When the verb in the if-clause is in the simple past tense, we use would + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "won't do",
                        "wouldn't do",
                        "wouldn't have done"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ………………………. red and green, you will get yellow.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "mix",
                        "will mix",
                        "would mix"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Unless you ……………………….. smoking, you will get cancer.",
                    "description": "Unless means if not.",
                    "answers": [
                        "quit",
                        "don't quit",
                        "won't quit"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you …………………………. your ways, you will land in serious trouble.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "not mend",
                        "mend",
                        "don't mend"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you had called me, I ………………………. come immediately.",
                    "description": "\r\nIn the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will",
                        "would",
                        "would have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you start now, you ………………………. there on time.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "will reach",
                        "would reach",
                        "would have reached"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I learned electronics at college, I ………………………… an engineer.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "can become",
                        "could become",
                        "could have become"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Unless you stop drinking, you ……………………….. liver trouble.",
                    "description": "Unless means if not. This sentence can also be written as: If you do not stop drinking, you will develop liver trouble.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "will develop",
                        "will not develop"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you see him, ………………………… him to visit me?",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "will you ask",
                        "would you ask",
                        "would you have asked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ………………………. into James, tell him that I am getting married.",
                    "description": "We can use should in the first conditional to suggest that something is very unlikely.",
                    "answers": [
                        "run",
                        "should run",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If he ……………………… late, we will have to leave without him.",
                    "description": "Should is possible in the first conditional.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "should be",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "What would you do if you …………………….. to lose your job?",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "are",
                        "were",
                        "had been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}